Granville Hicks Papers
Granville Hicks Papers
- Writings
  - Articles
    - American Way book review: "The Far Side of Success,", Dec. 1974; Leggett, John. Ross and Tom: Two American Tragedies (Box 75)
    - American Way book review: Guest, Judith. Ordinary People. (Box 75)
    - American Way book review: Heller, Joseph. Something Happened, Nov. 1974 (Box 75)
    - American Way book review: Lewis, R.W.B. Edith Wharton: a Biography. (Box 75)
    - American Way book review: "A Life of Unlearning", June 1974 (Box 75)
    - American Way book review: Macdonald, Ross. Great Stories of Suspense, Mar. 1975 (Box 75)
    - American Way book review: "Midsummer Dreams", July 1974 (Box 75)
    - American Way book review: Muggeridge, Malcolm. Chronicles of Wasted Time, Oct. 1974 (Box 75)
    - American Way book review: Nicolson, Nigel. Portrait of a Marriage / Clive, Mary. This Sun of York, Mar. 1974 (Box 75)
    - American Way book review: "P.G. Wodehouse,", Mar. 1976 (Box 75)
    - American Way book review: Powell. Anthony. Hearing Secret Harmonies (Box 75)
    - American Way book review: "Promises to Keep", Jan. 1974 (Box 75)
    - American Way book review: Rofheart, Martha. The Alexandrian. (Box 75)
    - American Way book review: Roth, Philip. My Life as a Man / Baldwin, James. If Beale Street Could Talk, Aug. 1974 (Box 75)
    - American Way book review: "A Sense of Direction,", Apr. 1974 (Box 75)
    - American Way book review: Swados, Harvey. Celebration / Matthiessen, Peter. Far Tortuga, June 1975 (Box 75)
    - American Way book review: "Through a Glass Darkly", Feb. 1974 (Box 75)
    - American Way book review: Updike, John, Buchanan Dying / Burgess, Anthony. Napoleon Symphony, Sept. 1974 (Box 75)
    - American Way book review: Updike, John. A Month of Sundays, Apr. 1975 (Box 75)
    - American Way book review: "Victorian Vistas", Sept. 1975; Hargrave, Leonie. Clara Reeve / Moore, Brian. The Great Victorian Collection (Box 75)
    - American Way book review: "What is Fiction? What is Fact?", July 1975 (Box 75)
    - American Way book review: "What Strange Ingredients", May 1975 (Box 75)
    - American Way book review: "Writing What You Believe", Oct. 1973 (Box 75)
    - "America's Best Poets." The New Leader, Jan. 15, 1951 (Box 75)
    - "Are Loyalty Oaths Necessary?" New York State Education, Jan. 1967 (Box 75)
    - "Arnold Toynbee: The Boldest Historian." Harper's Magazine, 1947? (Box 75)
    - "Arthur Koestler and the Future of the Left." The Antioch Review, Summer 1945 (Box 75)
    - "Arthur Koestler's Despair." The New Leader, Mar. 26, 1951 (Box 75)
    - "Assumptions in Literature." The English Journal, Nov. 1936 (Box 75)
    - "An Austrian and a French Novelist Scrutinize the Nature of Man." The New Leader, July 6, 1953 (Box 75)
    - "A Belated Tribute to Short Stories by Eudora Welty and Flannery O'Connor." The New Leader, Aug. 15, 1955 (Box 75)
    - "The Best American Novels Since 1945." The New Leader, Dec. 14, 1953 (Box 75)
    - "The Blind Alley of Marxism." The Nation, Sept. 28, 1940 (Box 75)
    - "C.P. Snow's 'Homecoming' Describes Social as well as Individual Problems." The New Leader, Oct. 22, 1956 (Box 75)
    - "'The Caine Mutiny,' Now on Screen, Again Raises Problem of Authority." The New Leader, Sept. 20, 1954 (Box 75)
    - "Campaigning for Browder." Pacific Weekly, Nov. 1936 (Box 75)
    - "Campus Cross-Section." The New Leader, Sept. 15, 1952 (Box 75)
    - "Can Writers Teach Writers?" Tomorrow, Feb. 1949 (Box 75)
    - "Capitalist Mass Society Indicted Anew in Erich Fromm's 'The Sane Society.'" The New Leader, Sept. 19, 1955 (Box 75)
    - "The Captive School." The Social Frontier, Oct. 1935 (Box 75)
    - "Carl Sandburg: Immigrant's Son Who Sang of America's Greatness." The New Leader, Jan. 26, 1953 (Box 75)
    - "The Case Against Willa Cather." The English Journal, Nov. 1933 (Box 75)
    - "A Challenge to Autocracy." The Literary Review, Aug. 11, 1923 (Box 75)
    - "The Changing Novel." Journal of the Otto Rank Association, June 1970 (Box 75)
    - "A Christian Literatus." The American Mercury, undated (Box 75)
    - "A Chronicle of Current Fiction." The New Leader, Feb. 25, 1952 (Box 75)
    - "A Chronicle of Current Fiction." The New Leader, Mar. 24, 1952 (Box 75)
    - "The Church in the Community." Education, undated (Box 75)
    - "Class Justice in the U.S.S.R." The Labor Defender, 1935? (Box 75)
    - "Collections of New and Classic Works by Saul Bellow, Orwell and Wilder." The New Leader, Nov. 26, 1956 (Box 75)
    - "Communism and Academic Freedom." The Christian Leader, Feb. 1, 1936 (Box 75)
    - "Communism and Academic Freedom." The Christian Register, Jan. 1936 (Box 75)
    - "Communism and Academic Freedom." The Christian Leader reader response (Box 75)
    - "Communism and the American Intellectuals." Whose Revolution, 1941 (Box 75)
    - "Compassion and Manipulation Depicted by a Young Novelist and an Old Pro." The New Leader, Feb. 28, 1955 (Box 75)
    - "Conclusions on 'Love and the Intellectuals'." The New Leader, Sept. 8, 1952 (Box 75)
    - "Conrad After Five Years." The New Republic, Jan. 8, 1930 (Box 75)
    - "A Contrast in Form." The New Leader, Sept. 29, 1952 (Box 75)
    - "A Conversation in Boston." The Sewanee Review, Apr. 1931 (Box 75A)
    - "The Conversion of John Hay." The New Republic, June 10, 1931 (Box 75A)
    - "The Critical Principles of vol. L. Parrington." Science and Society, Fall 1939 (Box 75A)
    - "Democracy Today and Tomorrow." Northwestern University on the Air, Apr. 4, 1942 (Box 75A)
    - "The Dilemmas of a Critic." The Forum, 1932 (Box 75A)
    - "A Discussion of 'Intransigent Radicalism' and 'Critical Liberalism.'" The New Leader, Feb. 8, 1954 (Box 75A)
    - "The Disinherited" by Jack Conroy. Partisan Review, Feb./Mar. 1934 (Box 75A)
    - "The Disturbing Problem of 'Genius': New Studies of Proust and Faulkner." The New Leader, Apr. 12, 1954 (Box 75A)
    - "Do Congress Red Probes Accomplish Objectives?" Brooklyn Daily Eagle, 1953? (Box 75A)
    - "Do Writers and Rural Living Mix? A Discussion by an Old Hand." The New Leader, Jan. 12, 1953 (Box 75A)
    - "Dr. Channing and the Creole Case." The American Historical Review, Apr. 1932 (Box 75A)
    - "Does the 'Tired Business Man' Need a Kinsey?" For The Record, Nov. 10, 1954 (Box 75A)
    - "Donald Elder's Biography Helps Solve Mysteries of Ring Lardner." The New Leader, July 2, 1956 (Box 75A)
    - "Dos Passos as a Lecturer." The New Leader, Dec. 11, 1950 (Box 75A)
    - "Dos Passos' Gifts." The New Republic, June 24, 1931 (Box 75A)
    - "Dylan Thomas and George Orwell - So Different, Yet in One Way So Alike." The New Leader, Dec. 26, 1955 (Box 75A)
    - "Efectos del Maquinismo en un Pueblo de los Estados Unidos." Cuadernos, 1954? (Box 75A)
    - "Ellen Glasgow's Autobiography Reveals a Sensitive Woman Dogged by Tragedy." The New Leader, Nov. 15, 1954 (Box 75A)
    - "'The Emigrants' by George Lamming - A Colorful New Novel of Alienation." The New Leader, Apr. 25, 1955 (Box 75A)
    - "The Enemies of Literature." The New Leader, May 5, 1952 (Box 75A)
    - "Ernest Hemingway and His Critics." The New Leader, Nov. 6, 1950 (Box 75A)
    - "Eudora Welty." The English Journal, Nov. 1952 (Box 75A)
    - "Everyone Analyzes Everyone Else in Mary McCarthy's 'A Charmed Life.'" The New Leader, Nov. 7, 1955 (Box 75A)
    - "Ex-Communist Comments on Investigations." Philadelphia Evening Bulletin, 1953? (Box 75A)
    - "The Ex-Communist Novel." The New Leader, July 23, 1951 (Box 75A)
    - "The Failure of Left Criticism." The New Republic, Sept. 9, 1940 (Box 76)
    - "Faulkner and His Town." Saturday Review, Oct. 2, 1965 (Box 76)
    - "Faulkner's Sequel to 'Sanctuary'." The New Leader, Oct. 22, 1951 (Box 76)
    - "Faulkner's South." The Georgia Review, Fall 1951 (Box 76)
    - "Fiction and Social Criticism." The English Journal, Apr. 1952 (Box 76)
    - "Fiction Chronicle." The New Leader, Nov. 26, 1951 (Box 76)
    - "Fiction Chronicle: Novels by Halevy, Ellison, Bonner, Gallagher and Goyen." The New Leader, Aug. 1, 1955 (Box 76)
    - "'The Field of Vision,' by Wright Morris, a Significant and Enriching Novel." The New Leader, Oct. 1, 1956 (Box 76)
    - "Fifteen Essays by James T. Farrell, Poetry and Prose by Dylan Thomas." The New Leader, Jan. 3, 1955 (Box 76)
    - "The Fighting Decade." The Saturday Review of Literature, July 6, 1940 (Box 76)
    - "A Fine New Novel by Mark Harris and Collected Stories of J.F. Powers." The New Leader, Mar. 26, 1956 (Box 76)
    - "Flat Tire" by Bob Reed The Literary Workshop, 1934; criticism (Box 76)
    - "Ford Madox Ford - A Neglected Contemporary." The Bookman, Dec. 1930 (Box 76)
    - "Freedom to Criticize Existing Institutions." The Social Frontier, Mar. 1936 (Box 76)
    - "The Future of Socialism II: On Ideas and Attitudes." Partisan Review, 1946? (Box 76)
    - "Generations of the Fifties: Malamud, Gold, and Updike." The Creative Present, 1963; edited by N. Balakian and C. Simmons, (draft) (Box 76)
    - "Generations of the Fifties: Malamud, Gold, and Updike." The Creative Present, 1963; edited by N. Balakian and C. Simmons (Box 76)
    - "Giono, Camus and the 'Anchor Review' Concern Themselves With Man's Fate." The New Leader, Oct. 24, 1955 (Box 76)
    - "A Glance at Channing's Friendships." The Christian Register, Sept. 5, 1929; Sept. 12, 1929 (Box 76)
    - "A Grasping Imagination." The Sewanee Review, Summer (Box 76)
    - "The Great Debate Pt.II: Progressives and the War" (Box 76)
    - "The Great Reversal." The New Leader, Mar. 29, 1954 (Box 76)
    - "The Ground Alfred Kazin Stands On." The Antioch Review, Spring 1943 (Box 76)
    - "The Gutter - And Then What?" The Forum, Dec. 1928 (Box 76)
    - "Harris's 'Ticket for a Seamstitch' and Gill's 'The Day the Money Stopped.'" The New Leader, Feb. 25, 1957 (Box 76)
    - "Harvard and the Interest Rate." The New Republic, June 1939 (Box 76)
    - "Hicks Nails a Lie." New Masses, Feb. 1939 (Box 76)
    - "'A House of Children,' by Joyce Cary, and David Garnett's 'Aspects of Love.'" The New Leader, Apr. 9, 1956 (Box 76)
    - "How Red Was the Red Decade?" Harper's Magazine, 1953? (Box 76)
    - "How We Live Now in America." Commentary, Dec. 1953 (Box 76)
    - "Howard Fast's One-Man Reformation." The English Journal, Sept. 1945 (Box 76)
    - "Ignazio Silone's New Novel Depicts the Postwar Peasants of the Abruzzi." The New Leader, Oct. 19, 1953 (Box 76)
    - "Immigrant's Progress." The New Leader, July 21, 1952 (Box 76)
    - "The Impressive Debut of a Versatile Writer, 25 year-old Shirley Ann Grau." The New Leader, Jan. 31, 1955 (Box 76)
    - "In A Novel It's the Life, Not the Politics, That Counts." New York Times Book Review, Aug. 12, 1956 (Box 76)
    - "Industry and the Imagination." South Atlantic Quarterly, Apr. 1929 (Box 76)
    - "The Inimitable Faulkner." The New Leader, Aug. 4, 1952 (Box 76)
    - "'The Innocent,' A Vigorous, Readable Southern Novel by Madison Jones." The New Leader, Mar. 11, 1957 (Box 76)
    - "The Intransigence of Edmund Wilson." The Antioch Review, Winter 1947 (Box 76)
    - "The Invasion of Privacy (3)." The American Scholar, Spring 1959 (Box 76)
    - "Irresponsibilities: 1949." The New Leader, June 11, 1949 (Box 76)
    - "Irving Howe's 'Politics and the Novel' - Intelligent, Appreciative Criticism." The New Leader, Mar. 25, 1957 (Box 76)
    - "Is McCarthyism a Phantom?" The New Leader, June 4, 1951 (Box 76)
    - "Is Non-Fiction More 'Serious' Than Ficiton? Some Philistines Think So." The New Leader, July 11, 1955 (Box 76)
    - "Is War Necessary?" The Universalist Herald, Apr. 15, 1925 (Box 76)
    - "Ivy Compton-Burnett's 'Brothers and Sisters' Combines Artistry, Insight." The New Leader, Jan. 7, 1957 (Box 76)
    - "J.C. Furnas on Anti-Negro Bias, Earl Conrad on the Young Seward." The New Leader, July 16, 1956 (Box 76)
    - "Jacques Barzun Examines America - Its Techniques, Its Culture, Its Values." The New Leader, May 10, 1954 (Box 76)
    - "James Baldwin's Promising First Novel, 'Go Tell It on the Mountain.'" The New Leader, June 1, 1953 (Box 76)
    - "John Cheever's 'Wapshot Chronicle' and Two Novels by Younger Writers." The New Leader, Apr. 8, 1957 (Box 76)
    - "John Dos Passos." The Bookman, Apr. 1932 (Box 76)
    - "John Hersey Bogs Down in Symbolism in New Novel About a Small Town." The New Leader, Nov. 30, 1953 (Box 76)
    - "John Phillips, Oakley Hall, Allan Seager Speak Up for Our Dissatisfied Youth." The New Leader, May 18, 1953 (Box 76)
    - "John Reed and Teddy Roosevelt." New Masses, Dec. 3, 1935 (Box 76)
    - "John Reed and the Jingo Press." New Masses, Jan. 14, 1936 (Box 76)
    - "John Reed and the Old Masses." New Masses, Dec. 31, 1935 (Box 76)
    - "John Reed and the World War." New Masses, Nov. 26, 1935 (Box 76)
    - "John Reed in Czarist Russia." New Masses, Dec. 17, 1935 (Box 76)
    - "John Reed's Three Journeys." Soviet Russia Today, Nov. 1936 (Box 76)
    - "Joyce Cary Concludes His Trilogy Tragically with 'Not Honour More.'" The New Leader, June 13, 1955 (Box 76)
    - "Landlord Cooper and the Anti-Renters." The Antioch Review, undated (Box 76)
    - "A Late Look at 1956 Novels by John Hersey, Eva Boros and Iris Murdoch." The New Leader, Jan. 14, 1957 (Box 76)
    - "Lattimore and the Liberals." The New Leader, May 27, 1950 (Box 76)
    - "Leslie Fiedler's 'End to Innocence' - Tart Essays on Literature, Politics." The New Leader, June 27, 1955 (Box 76)
    - "Letters of Edna St. Vincent Millay, Sinclair Lewis and Hart Crane." The New Leader, Dec. 15, 1952 (Box 77)
    - "Letters to Dr. Channing on Slavery and the Annexation of Texas, 1837." The New England Quarterly, 1932 (Box 77)
    - "Letters to William Francis Channing." American Literature, Nov. 1930 (Box 77)
    - "Liberalism in the Fifties." The American Scholar, Summer 1956 (Box 77)
    - "Liberals Fake and Retarded." The New Leader, Mar. 22, 1954 (Box 77)
    - "The Liberals Who Haven't Learned." Commentary, 1951? (Box 77)
    - "Lin Yutang's Tale of Two Lovers - Romance Against a Chinese Backdrop." The New Leader, Aug. 10, 1953 (Box 77)
    - "Lincoln Steffens: He Covered the Future." Commentary, Feb. 1952; notes (Box 77)
    - "Lincoln Steffens: He Covered the Future." Commentary, Feb. 1952; draft I (Box 77)
    - "Lincoln Steffens: He Covered the Future." Commentary, Feb. 1952; draft II (Box 77)
    - "Lincoln Steffens: He Covered the Future." Commentary, Feb. 1952 (Box 77)
    - "Literary Expression and the Health of Society." The English Journal, Mar. 1938 (Box 77)
    - "A Literary Opposition to Utilitarianism." Science and Society, Summer 1937 (Box 77)
    - "A Literary Pilgrimage." America Illustrated, no. 74, 1962 (Box 77)
    - "A Literary Swell." American Mercury, undated (Box 77)
    - "Literature and Revolution." The English Journal, Mar. 1935 (Box 77)
    - "Literature and the War." College English, Dec. 1939 (Box 77)
    - "Literature in this Global War." The English Journal, May 1943 (Box 77)
    - "Little Man, What Absurdity Now?" Saturday Review, Apr. 14, 1962 (Box 77)
    - "Local History." Wisconsin Magazine of History, Autumn 1952 (Box 77)
    - "LONDRES, by Paul Morand", undated (Box 77)
    - "A Look at the Novel." Today's Education, Apr. 1969 (Box 77)
    - "McCarthy and the Homosexuals." The New Leader, June 17, 1950 (Box 77)
    - "MacKinlay Kantor's 'Andersonville' and 'A Dream of Kings' by Davis Grubb." The New Leader, Jan. 9, 1956 (Box 77)
    - "MacLeish's False Dilemma." The New Leader, Mar. 24, 1952 (Box 77)
    - "A Man I Used to Write To." The New Leader, Dec. 4, 1950 (Box 77)
    - "'The Man Who Was Not With It' and Other Novels by Herbert Gold." The New Leader, Feb. 20, 1956 (Box 77)
    - "Margaret Fuller to Sarah Helen Whitman: An Unpublished Letter." American Literature, Jan. 1930 (Box 77)
    - "Marquand of Newburyport." Harper's Magazine, Apr. 1950; draft I (Box 77)
    - "Marquand of Newburyport." Harper's Magazine, Apr. 1950; draft II (Box 77)
    - "Marquand of Newburyport." Harper's Magazine, Apr. 1950 (Box 77)
    - Marxist criticism discussion. Partisan Review, Apr./May 1935 (Box 77)
    - "Men and Women of Letters." The New Leader, Mar. 10, 1952 (Box 77)
    - "Men With a Vision." The New Leader, Apr. 21, 1952 (Box 77)
    - "The Mind of a Small Town." The American Mercury, 1946? (Box 77)
    - "Mr. Hicks Launches New Feature With Discussion of Edmund Wilson." The New Leader, Dec. 1, 1952 (Box 77)
    - "Modern Literature and the War." Fight, Feb. 1934 (Box 77)
    - "A Modern Reworking of the 'Odyssey' and a Jewish Family's Life in Wales." The New Leader, Mar. 14, 1955 (Box 77)
    - "Morris Ernst's New Book Predicts Pie in the Sky Within Two Decades." The New Leader, Nov. 21, 1955 (Box 77)
    - "My Favorite Forgotten Book." Tomorrow, Sept. 1946 (Box 77)
    - "The Mystery of the Best Seller." The English Journal, Oct. 1934 (Box 77)
    - "Myth and Reality in Three Barthian Worlds." Newsday, Sept. 24, 1972 (Box 77)
    - "A 'Nation' Still Divided." The New Leader, Aug. 5, 1950 (Box 77)
    - "Nelson Algren's Solid, Convincing 'Walk on the Wild Side' and Four Other Novels." The New Leader, May 28, 1956 (Box 77)
    - "The 'New' Criticism: Allen Tate Defends, Van Wyck Brooks Attacks." The New Leader, Apr. 27, 1953 (Box 77)
    - "New Directions on the Left." The New Republic, June 17, 1940 (Box 77)
    - "New Literary Editor Comes to Defense of Book Reviewers and Book Reviewing." The New Leader, Nov. 12, 1951 (Box 77)
    - "New Novels of Current Politics by Edwin O'Connor, Richard Llewellyn." The New Leader, Feb. 6, 1956 (Box 77)
    - "New Paper-back Anthology Brings Serious Writing to New Readers." The New Leader, Nov. 2, 1953 (Box 77)
    - New York Times Book Review: Auchincloss, Louis. I Come As a Thief, Sep 3, 1972 (Box 77)
    - New York Times Book Review: Bailey, Anthony. In the Village, Aug 29, 1971 (Box 77)
    - New York Times Book Review: Halper, Albert. Goodbye Union Square, Nov 8, 1970 (Box 77)
    - New York Times Book Review: Halpert, Stephen (ed.) A Return to Pagan y, Oct 26, 1969 (Box 77)
    - New York Times Book Review: Hersey, John. My Petition for More Space, Sep 22, 1974 (Box 77)
    - New York Times Book Review: Kazan, Elia. The Assassins, Mar 5, 1972 (Box 77)
    - New York Times Book Review: Levin, Meyer. The Settlers, Apr 23, 1972 (Box 77)
    - New York Times Book Review: Morris, Wright. Fire Sermon, Sep 26, 1971 (Box 77)
    - New York Times Book Review: Packard, Vance. A Nation of Strangers, Sep 10, 1972 (Box 77)
    - New York Times Book Review: Rofheart, Martha. Fortune Made His Sword, Feb 27, 1972 (Box 77)
    - New York Times Book Review: Rosskam, Edwin. Roosevelt, New Jersey, Jul 30, 1972 (Box 77)
    - New York Times Book Review: Schmitt, Gladys. The Godforgotten, Aug 20, 1972 (Box 77)
    - New York Times Book Review: Wilder, Thornton. Theophilus North, Oct 21, 1973 (Box 77)
    - New York Times Book Review: Wouk, Herman. The Winds of War, Nov 14, 1971 (Box 77)
    - "The 'New Yorker,' Anthony West and the Sad State of Literary Journalism." The New Leader, May 14, 1956 (Box 77)
    - "1955's Young Novelists Say Farewell to Old Timidity on Social Themes." The New Leader, Dec. 12, 1955 (Box 77)
    - "1954's Novelists Treat the Theme of 'Here and There,' 'Now and Then.'" The New Leader, Dec. 13, 1954 (Box 77)
    - "A Note on Literary Journalism, and Good Novels by Moore and Malamud." The New Leader, Apr. 29, 1957 (Box 77)
    - "The Novel Isn't Dying." The New Leader, Dec. 10, 1951 (Box 77)
    - "A Novel of Despair from Spain and a Buoyant One from France." The New Leader, Jan. 25, 1954 (Box 77)
    - "Novelist Bernard Malamud." America Illustrated, no. 109, 1965 (Box 77)
    - "Novelist Herbert Gold." America Illustrated, no. 52, 1961 (Box 77)
    - "Novelist Wright Morris." America Illustrated, 1965 (Box 77)
    - "A Novelist's Meditation on History." Dialogue, vol. 1, no. 1, 1968 (Box 77)
    - "Novels by Graham Greene, David Karp Describe American Political Innocence." The New Leader, Mar. 12, 1956 (Box 77)
    - "Novels by Robert Coates, Jo Sinclair, Felix Jackson and Peter Matthiessen." The New Leader, Oct. 10, 1955 (Box 77)
    - "Novels by Robert Graves, Bernard Wolfe, H.M. Lynde and John Wyllie." The New Leader, July 8, 1957 (Box 77)
    - "Of Bad Weather in the Country." The New Leader, Apr. 9, 1951 (Box 78)
    - "Of Birds and Ships and Democracy." The New Leader, Aug. 6, 1951 (Box 78)
    - "Of Good Weather in the Country." The New Leader, July 16, 1951 (Box 78)
    - "Orwell's 'Keep the Aspidistra Flying' and Nigel Dennis's 'Cards of Identity.'" The New Leader, Jan. 23, 1956 (Box 78)
    - "Our First Novelist." The New Leader, Nov. 20, 1950 (Box 78)
    - "Our Novelists' Shifting Reputations." The English Journal, Jan. 1951 (Box 78)
    - "Owen Lattimore and Louis Budenz." The New Leader, May 6, 1950 (Box 78)
    - "P-N Fiction." College English, Dec. 1946 (Box 78)
    - "Paleface in the Cheyenne Camp." Saturday Review, Oct. 10, 1964 (Box 78)
    - "The Parsons and the War." The American Mercury, Feb. 1927 (Box 78)
    - "Party Lines and Dial Phones." The New Leader, Sept. 23, 1950 (Box 78)
    - "The Past and Future of William Faulkner." The Bookman, Sept. 1931 (Box 78)
    - "Peter Forges Ahead." New York Times Book Review, 1954 (Box 78)
    - "'Peyton Place' and Other Fictional Treatments of Small-Town U.S.A." The New Leader, Oct. 29, 1956 (Box 78)
    - "A Pilgrimage of Sorts." Saturday Review, July 22, 1961 (Box 78)
    - "A Plea for Intellect." The New Leader, July 6, 1959 (Box 78)
    - "A Pleasant Dream." New Republic, July 8, 1972; photocopy (Box 78)
    - "The Poems and Plays of T.S. Eliot and an Omnibus of Stephen Crane." The New Leader, Dec. 29, 1952 (Box 78)
    - "Political Apathy in America." The University of Chicago Round Table, Oct. 29, 1950 (Box 78)
    - "Political Interlude." Interim, 1949-1950? (Box 78)
    - "Political Novels by Joseph Wechsberg, Ralph de Toledano and May Sarton." The New Leader, Mar. 28, 1955 (Box 78)
    - "The Politics of John Dos Passos." The Antioch Review, undated (Box 78)
    - "The Portrait of a Victim." The Sewanee Review, Summer 1950 (Box 78)
    - "The Prize Short Stories of the Year and Three New Individual Collections." The New Leader, Feb. 11, 1957 (Box 78)
    - "Prize Stories 1968: The O. Henry Awards" Book Review Mundus Artium (Box 78)
    - "Problems of American Fellow Travelers." International Literature, no. 3., 1933 (Box 78)
    - "A Profound Study of Hemingway, and Miscellany by Sinclair Lewis." The New Leader, Mar. 2, 1953 (Box 78)
    - "Progressives and the War." The Harvard Progressive, Apr. 1941 (Box 78)
    - "The Question of William Faulkner: His New Novel, 'The Town,' as Test." The New Leader, May 13, 1957 (Box 78)
    - "'The Radical Novel in the United States,' a Critical Survey by Walter B. Rideout." The New Leader, Nov. 12, 1956 (Box 78)
    - "Recent Congressional Witness Backs Plan to Investigate the Investigators." The New Leader, Apr. 13, 1953 (Box 78)
    - "The Red (?) Thirties Illuminated in Murray Kempton's 'Part of Our Time.'" The New Leader, May 16, 1955 (Box 78)
    - "Reflections of a Small-Towner." The Georgia Review, 1947? (Box 78)
    - "The Reputation of James Gould Cozzens." The English Journal, Jan. 1950 (Box 78)
    - "Review of 1950 in Literature." The New Leader, Jan. 29, 1951 (Box 78)
    - "The Rich, Warm Autobiography of Henry James - Now All in One Volume." The New Leader, June 18, 1956 (Box 78)
    - "Robert Herrick, Liberal." The New Republic, June 17, 1931 (Box 78)
    - "Robert Penn Warren's Verse Dialogue with Thomas Jefferson." The New Leader, Oct. 5, 1953 (Box 78)
    - "Der Romancier und die Macht." Literatur, 1952? (Box 78)
    - "Roxborough, Post-Truman." Commentary, Mar. 1953 (Box 78)
    - "Rural America in Literature." America Illustrated, no. 84, 1963 (Box 78)